ICC Lombard, this is the stock which is
in tremendous action today, double digital is engaged in
Chalang Jabardti Ji Banti is seen,
Varun is telling the reason for the rise, please tell me, the energy
news that has come today is that ICC Bank is going to
increase its stake in ICC Lombard by 4% and
by September 2024, this stake will
first increase to around 25%, now it is going to
increase more than this by only 4%,
why did the stock rise by 10%, see you will
remember that in 2019, RBI had brought a circular
where all the banks were told to
reduce their stake in all their insurance subsidies, after that ICC
Lombard had a deal with Indian Exchange,
under that deal, the stake of around 4% was
reduced and this happened in September 2021
when the bank's stake in ICC Lombard had
reduced to 48% and only then
they had taken approval from IRDA that
yes, our stake will be
reduced by
30% at the loss of 8%  They will take it up to 18%,
which means they were going to reduce their stake further.
Okay, you might remember that recently
due to the Mozar of HDFC Bank and HDFC, RBI allowed HDFC Bank to keep
its stake in Live and Organ more than 50%
and
after this it was triggered that perhaps ICC
Bank will also increase its stake. In
fact, on 10th March, RBI had
written a You Know letter to ICC that if you
need more time to reduce your stake then you can think about it and after that today
finally ICC Bank said that we will
not reduce it in Lombard but will increase it by
around 8%. So firstly there has been a flood and
secondly the hangover of reducing the 18%
stake is over now
and for this you are watching how to make a
great pick up in the world in the stock
[Music]